Guide to the Henry Seidel Canby Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1879-58; Series III; 12; (19 boxes)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Unidentified
      - "Talking on Trains," printed version, n.d.
      - "Tear Down the Universities," printed version, 1921 [Aug] 9
      - "Why Not?" printed version, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 768)
      - Untitled poem, autograph ms., 1906 May 27
      - Untitled poem, autograph ms., [ca. 1912]
      - Fragment, printed version, 1920
- Lecture Notes and Related Course Materials, 1900-43; Series IV; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Series IV, Lecture Notes and Related Course Materials, (Boxes 32-34) is divided into four subseries: Author Courses, Topical Courses, and General English Composition Courses, and Other Course Materials. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically by subject. Unidentified lecture notes and miscellaneous curriculum material are filed at the end of the series.
  - AUTHOR COURSES
    - Addison, Joseph, 1916 (Box 32, Folder 769)
    - Bacon, Francis, 1913-15, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 770)
    - Browning, Robert, 1912 (Box 32, Folder 771)
    - Burns, Robert, 1908-17 (Box 32, Folder 772)
    - Byron, George Gordon, Byron, Baron, 1908-12, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 773)
    - Carlyle, Thomas, 1907-12, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 774-775)
    - Chaucer, Geoffrey, 1909-15 (Box 32, Folder 776-779)
    - France, Anatole, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 780)
    - Homer, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 781)
    - Marlowe, Christopher, 1909-15, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 782-783)
    - Milton, John, 1910-14 (Box 32, Folder 784)
    - Pope, Alexander, 1913-16 (Box 32, Folder 785)
    - Shakespeare, William
      - Antony and Cleopatra, 1914-15 (Box 32, Folder 786)
      - King Lear, 1913-16 (Box 32, Folder 787)
      - A Midsummer Night's Dream, 1910 (Box 32, Folder 788)
      - Othello, 1915 (Box 32, Folder 789)
      - The Tempest, 1907-11 (Box 33, Folder 790)
      - Twelfth Night, 1907 (Box 33, Folder 791)
      - The Winter's Tale, 1907-08, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 792)
    - Spenser, Edmund, 1913-15, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 793)
    - Tennyson, Alfred Tennyson, Baron, 1907 May 10 (Box 33, Folder 794)
    - Thackeray, William Makepeace
      - Vanity Fair, 1912, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 795)
  - TOPICAL COURSES
    - Ballads, 1914, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 796)
    - The Bible, 1913-16. n.d. (Box 33, Folder 797)
    - Logic, 1909-10, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 798)
    - Short Story in English (No. 1), 1908-12, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 799-801)
    - Short Story in English (No. 2), 1907-13, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 802-803)
    - Short Story in English (No. 3), 1908-13 (Box 33, Folder 804-805)
  - GENERAL ENGLISH COMPOSITION COURSES
    - Freshman English, 1911-20 (Box 34, Folder 806-807)
    - Junior English Composition, 1911-19, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 808-810)
    - Types of Literature, 1911-14, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 811-812)
  - OTHER COURSE MATERIALS
    - Student papers, 1900, 1911 (Box 34, Folder 813)
    - Student examinations, 1919-20, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 814)
    - Unidentified lecture notes, 1913, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 815-817)
    - Other classroom materials, 1908-43, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 818)
- Personal Papers, 1825-1959; Series V; 1.75; (5 boxes)
  Series V, Personal Papers, (Boxes 35-39) is divided into four subseries: Diaries, Other Papers, Subject/Interest Files and Photographs. Diaries are arranged chronologically. The other subseries are arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - DIARIES
    - Diary, 1893 (Box 35, Folder 819)
    - Diary, 1897 (Box 35, Folder 820)
    - Diary, 1899 (Box 35, Folder 821)
    - Diary, 1911 (Box 35, Folder 822)
    - Diaries, 1912-13 (Box 35, Folder 823-824)
    - Diaries, 1914-15 (Box 35, Folder 825-26)
    - Diaries, 1916 (Box 35, Folder 827-28)
    - Diaries, 1917-20 (Box 35, Folder 829-31)
    - Diary, 1921, 1934 (Box 36, Folder 832)
    - Diary, 1937 (Box 36, Folder 833)
    - Diary, 1938 (Box 36, Folder 834)
    - Diaries, 1940-42 (Box 36, Folder 835-838)
    - Diaries, 1947 (Box 36, Folder 839-840)
    - Diary, 1948 (Box 36, Folder 841)
    - Diary, 1950 (Box 36, Folder 842)
    - Diary, n.y. [Feb-Oct?] (Box 36, Folder 843)
    - Diary, n.y. Jun-Sep (Box 36, Folder 844)
    - Diary, n.y. [Sep?] (Box 36, Folder 845)
    - Diaries, n.y. Jan-May (Box 37, Folder 846-850)
    - Diaries, n.y. Jun-Sep (Box 37, Folder 851-854)
    - Diary, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 855)
  - OTHER PAPERS
    - Address book, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 856)
    - Art
      - Caricatures of Henry Seidel Canby by Willis Birchman and William Gropper, 1927 Sep 7 (Box 37, Folder 857)
      - Caricature of Henry Seidel Canby by an unidentified artist, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 858)
      - Drawing of Henry Seidel Canby by Borchardt, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 859)
    - Australia memorabilia, 1941, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 860)
    - Biographical information, 1918-49, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 861)
    - Book-of-the-Month Club, 1943-56, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 862)
      See also: Oversize, Box 40, folder 921
    - Book plate, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 863)
    - Calling cards, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 864)
    - Canby, Edward T. (father): obituary, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 865)
    - Canby, Edward T. (son): birth announcement, n.d.
    - Carribean tour, 1948 (Box 37, Folder 866)
    - Committee service, 1918-58, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 867)
    - Degrees and Honors
      See also: Yale University
      - Doctor of Letters, Knox College, Galesburg, Illinois (newspaper article
        See: Oversize, Box 40, folder 922
      - Doctor of Letters, University of Delaware, Wilmington, Delaware (magazine and newspaper articles), 1946 Jun (Box 38, Folder 868)
        See also: Oversize, Box 40, folder 923
      - High School Diploma, Friends' School, Wilmington, Delaware
        See: Oversize, Box 40, folder 924
      - National Institute of Arts and Letters (membership certificate), 1931 (Box 38, Folder 869)
      - Royal Society of Literature (magazine article re election as fellow), 1951 Dec (Box 38, Folder 870)
      - Whittier Literary Society (membership certificate)
        See: Oversize, Box 40, folder 925
    - Dodd, L. Wilson (brother-in-law): obituary, 1933 (Box 38, Folder 871)
    - Financial papers
      - Checks, 1920 Sep 1-22 (Box 38, Folder 872)
      - Contracts, 1825, 1915 (Box 38, Folder 873)
      - Receipts, 1907 (Box 38, Folder 874)
      - Taxes, 1936 Jun 1 (Box 38, Folder 875)
    - Gause, Harry Taylor: obituary, [1925] (Box 38, Folder 876)
    - Gause family, Harry Taylor: return from tour of Europe, n.d.
    - Green, Natalie: wedding announcement, 1948 Mar
    - Lecturer: Henry Seidel Canby, brochure, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 877)
    - Obituary, 1961 Feb 7 (Box 38, Folder 878)
    - P.E.N. Club, 1933, 1935 (Box 38, Folder 879)
    - Programs: miscellaneous, 1903-52 (Box 38, Folder 880)
    - Time magazine, with Henry Seidel Canby on the cover, 1924 May 19 (Box 38, Folder 881)
    - Wedding list, [1907] (Box 38, Folder 882)
    - World War I (Box 38, Folder 883)
      - Draft board registration certificate, 1918 Sep 2
      - Identification card, 1918 Feb 8
      - Identity papers, American and French, 1918
      - Menu, 1918 May 21
      - Passport application, 1918 Jan 8
    - Yale University
      - "Commemorative Exercises in Honor of the Yale Men Who Gave Their Lives in the War": program, 1919 Jun 15 (Box 38, Folder 884)
      - Honors, 1946, 1958 (Box 38, Folder 885)
      - Ph.B., Yale University, New Haven, Connecticut (diploma)
        See: Oversize, Box 40, folder 926
      - Ph.D., Yale University, New Haven, Connecticut (diploma)
        See: Oversize, Box 40, folder 927
      - Reading lists, 1898-1911 (Box 38, Folder 886)
      - Statistical questions ('99 S.), 1899 (Box 38, Folder 887)
      - Student organizations, 1900 (Box 38, Folder 888)
      - Student papers, 1900, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 889-892)
      - Yale Courant, 1900 (Box 38, Folder 893)
      - Yale Review, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 894)
  - SUBJECT/INTEREST FILES
    - Atlantic Telegraph: first news Despatch, 1858 Aug 26 (Box 38, Folder 895)
    - Benét, William Rose: obituaries, 1950
    - "Dark Days Ahead. A Dialogue on the Bankruptcy of Business Leadership": printed version, 1930 Oct (Box 38, Folder 896)
    - The English-Speaking Union, 1918 Jul 4 (Box 38, Folder 897)
    - Ireland, 1918 (Box 38, Folder 898)
    - League of Nations, n.d.
    - Lowell, Amy, 1925 Apr 4
    - Mann, Thomas: clipping with remarks by Henry Seidel Canby, 1934 Jun 7 (Box 38, Folder 899)
    - Miscellaneous, 1852-1959, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 900)
    - New York Evening Post's literary review, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 901)
    - Political advertisement from 1940 presidential campaign in The New York Times against Wendel Wilkie by "A Committee of American Authors and Editors" (includes Henry Seidel Canby)
      See: Oversize, Box 40, folder 928
    - Porter, William Sidney (O. Henry): obituary, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 902)
    - Quakers See Oversize: Box 40, folder 929
      See also: Box 28, folders 559-561 [article by HSC, "Admiring..."]
    - Saturday Review of Literature, 1931-49, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 903)
    - Wilder, Thornton, 1962 May 6 (Box 39, Folder 904)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Canby, Henry Seidel
      - Childhood, 1881-92, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 905)
      - Adulthood, 1941, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 906)
      - Award presentation re The Saturday Review (includes Lewis Gannett, John Kieran, Clifton Fadiman, Franklin P. Adams, Henry Seidel Canby, and Oscar Levant), ca. 1950 (Box 39, Folder 907)
      - Independence Day celebration at Anglo-Saxon Fellowship meeting in Central Hall, Westminster, London, England (includes Winston Churchill, Admiral Sims, Lord Bruce, and Henry Seidel Canby), 1918 Jul 4 (Box 39, Folder 908)
      - U. S. Office of War Information, Sydney, Australia (includes Dixon Wector, Whitney Darrow, Henry Seidel Canby, Edward P. Hamilton, and Mrs. Dixon Wector), 1945 Jun 5 (Box 39, Folder 909)
      - Yale University: class reunion (1899 S.), 1944 (Box 39, Folder 910)
        See also: Oversize, Box 40, folder 930
    - Other photographs
      - Santayana, George, 1932 (Box 39, Folder 911)
      - Seymour, [Charles?], with a note, [19]33 Nov 18 (Box 39, Folder 912)
      - Unidentified, 1907-18, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 913)
- Oversize, 1895-1944; 2; (1 box)
  Oversize (Box 40), contains material from Series III and Series V, and is arranged in series order.
  - WRITINGS
    - Books
      - Thoreau: A Biography
        - Advertisements, ca. 1939 (Box 40 (Oversize), Folder 914)
      - Walt Whitman, An American
        - Dust jacket, n.d. (Box 40 (Oversize), Folder 915)
        - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 40 (Oversize), Folder 916)
    - Shorter Works
      - Articles, Essays, Speeches
        - "The Captured Hessian," The Youth's Companion: printed version, 1897 Mar 25 (Box 40 (Oversize), Folder 917)
        - "Conrad and Melville," The Literary Review: printed version, 1922 Feb 4 (Box 40 (Oversize), Folder 918)
        - "Cuatro Estodos de la Costa Atlántica": printed version, n.d. (Box 40 (Oversize), Folder 919)
        - "Hindu Influence In American Thought": printed version, photocopy, 1944 (Box 40 (Oversize), Folder 920)
  - PERSONAL PAPERS
    - Other Papers
      - Book-of-the-Month Club, ca. 1944 (Box 40 (Oversize), Folder 921)
      - Degrees and Honors
        - Doctor of Letters, Knox College, Galesburg, Illinois (newspaper article), 1927 Jan 12 (Box 40 (Oversize), Folder 922)
        - Doctor of Letters, University of Delaware, Wilmington, Delaware (diploma), 1946 Jun 17 (Box 40 (Oversize), Folder 923)
        - High School Diploma, Friends' School, Wilmington, Delaware (diploma), 1895 Jun 18 (Box 40 (Oversize), Folder 924)
        - Whittier Literary Society (membership certificate), 1896 Jan 17 (Box 40 (Oversize), Folder 925)
      - Yale University
        - Ph.B., Yale University, New Haven, Connecticut (diploma), 1899 Apr 27 (Box 40 (Oversize), Folder 926)
        - Ph.D., Yale University, New Haven, Connecticut (diploma), 1905 Apr 27 (Box 40 (Oversize), Folder 927)
    - Subject/Interest Files
      - Political advertisement from 1940 presidential campaign in The New York Times against Wendel Willkie by "A Committee of American Authors and Editors" (includes Henry Seidel Canby), 1940 Nov 2 (Box 40 (Oversize), Folder 928)
      - Quakers, ca. 1950 (Box 40 (Oversize), Folder 929)
    - Photographs
      - Yale University: class reunion (1899 S.), 1954 Jun, n.d. (Box 40 (Oversize), Folder 930)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 0.25; (1 box)
  Box 40, Restricted Fragile Papers, contains fragile originals. The material is arranged in folder order and may be seen only with the permission of the appropriate curator.
  - Box 1, folder 1 Box 1, folder 1 Box 1, folder 1 (Box 41, Folder 931)
  - Box 1, folder 11 Box 1, folder 25 (Box 41, Folder 932)
  - Box 1, folder 35 Box 1, folder 37 Box 1, folder 41 Box 1, folder 41 (Box 41, Folder 933)
  - Box 2, folder 46 Box 2, folder 52 Box 2, folder 53 (Box 41, Folder 934)
  - Box 2, folder 61 Box 2, folder 69 Box 2, folder 79 (Box 41, Folder 935)
  - Box 3, folder 86 (Box 41, Folder 936)
  - Box 3, folder 98 Box 3, folder 98 (Box 41, Folder 937)
  - Box 3, folder 99 (Box 41, Folder 938)
  - Box 3, folders 107-112 (Box 41, Folder 939)
  - Box 3, folder 115 Box 3, folder 115 Box 3, folder 117 (Box 41, Folder 940)
  - Box 5, folder 168 Box 5, folder 178 Box 5, folder 187 Box 5, folder 191 (Box 41, Folder 941)
  - Box 5, folder 197 Box 5, folder 199 (Box 41, Folder 942)
  - Box 16, folder 393 (Box 41, Folder 944)
  - Box 6, folder 201 Box 6, folder 211 Box 6, folder 226 (Box 41, Folder 943)
  - Box 30, folder 664 Box 30, folder 696 (Box 41, Folder 945)
  - Box 37, folder 867 (Box 41, Folder 946)